Guide to the Judy Richardson Papers, 1963-2014 RL.10177
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- United Church of Christ Commission for Racial Justice, 1982-1993; 2
  - Toxic Wastes and Race in the United States report and coverage, 1987 (Box 24)
  - Shaka Zulu protest, 1987 (Box 24)
- Children's Literature and Bookselling, 1963-2008; 4
  This series documents Richardson's work in children's literature and as a bookseller, including her time at Drum and Spear Bookstore, Maelezo Bookstore, and as a student and consultant for black children's education in the late 1960s through the 1970s. There are four subseries: Drum and Spear, which contains legal, administrative, financial, and marketing/publicity documents from the operation of the bookstore; Maelezo, including its materials from its founding and opening as well as Richardson's work on an Annotated Children's Bibliography on behalf of the store; Education and Coursework, which includes class assignments, application materials, and projects by Richardson relating to her coursework on children's education; and Children Are Many Colors, Inc., a subseries documenting Richardson's work for the Third World Children's Book and Film Festival, held in Boston in 1980.
  - Drum and Spear Bookstore, 1963-2008; 7
    - Marketing, publicity, and newletters, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
    - Lawsuit, 1971 (Box 8)
      re: Drum and Spear Bookstore
    - Legal Papers, 1971-1973 (Box 8)
    - News Clippings, 1970-2008 (Box 8)
    - Catalog, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Purchasing catalog, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Children's book reviews for Drum and Spear, 1963-1972 (Box 8)
    - Children's book reviews by Richardson, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - "For Children" columns for Third World newspaper, 1973 (Box 23)
      Includes issues for Jan. 5, Jan. 26, Feb. 9, Mar. 30, Apr. 13, and Apr. 27 1973.
    - Cliff Alexander's Black on White TV show transcript, 1973 (Box 8)
      Featuring Richardson as an episode's guest.
    - Business correspondence, 1968-1977 (Box 8)
    - Financial reports, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - Store shopping bags, undated (Box 8)
    - Proposals and recommendations, undated (Box 8)
    - Store closing, undated (Box 8)
    - Children's workshops, undated (Box 8)
    - Drum and Spear Press manuscripts, undated (Box 8)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 8)
    - Loose notes, undated (Box 8)
    - Children's Drawing Contest poster, 1969 (Box 22, Box 23)
  - Maelezo Bookstore, 1972-1974; 8
    - Photograph: Opening of Maelezo Bookstore, undated (Box 8)
    - Maelezo Bookstore SBA Loan Agreement and other documents, 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - Copyright certificates for Black Children's Books, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Black Children's Books: an overview, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Annotated Children's Bibliography, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - Notes and drafts for Annotated Bibliography and Book Reviews, undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Education and Coursework, 1963-1977; 9
    - Reading in the Elementary School, 1975 (Box 8)
      papers, data, and correspondence
    - Howard University class assignments, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Autobiography, 1975 (Box 8)
      University Without Walls
    - Howard University study of racism and sexism in children's books, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Log summaries and self-evaluation of progress, 1975 July 25-1976 April 12 (Box 8)
    - Self-evaluation and project proposals/outlinea for University Without Walls, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Proposal drafts for Black Children's Literature Guide, undated (Box 8)
    - Correspondence re: financial aid and documents, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Transcripts, 1963-1975 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous documents re: education, 1977 and undated (Box 8)
    - Evaluations of Judy Richardson's performance in her course at Antioch, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Paper, draft, notes: The Chemical Components of Air Pollution and Its Effects on Human Life, undated (Box 8)
    - Columbia University materials, 1963-1966 (Box 8)
      correspondence re: financial aid, grades, application, coursework
    - Pamphlets re: education, undated (Box 8)
    - Suzanne's Coloring Calendar, 1976 (Box 23)
  - Children Are Many Colors, Inc., 1977-1981; 10
    - Research for incorporating Children Are Many Colors, undated (Box 9)
    - Incorporation papers for Children Are Many Colors, Inc., 1980 Oct. 30 (Box 9)
    - Letterhead, undated (Box 9)
    - Mass mailing soliciting vendors for Third World Book and Film Festival, undated (Box 9)
    - Grant information, Massachusetts Council on the Arts and Humanities, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Grant application for the Third World Book and Film Festival, 1980 May (Box 9)
    - Proposal and letters of support for the festival, undated (Box 9)
    - Harriet Tubman House involvement in festival, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 9)
    - Third World Children's Book and Film Festival miscellaneous documents, 1980; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Photographs and slides from the festival, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Panelist correspondence for the festival, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Publicity for the Third World Children's Book and Film Festival, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Buttons for the Third World Children's Book and Film Festival, 1980; 4 buttons (Box 9)
    - Promotional material for the festival (Box 9)
    - Correspondence re: planning, grant, and production of the festival, 1978-1981 and undated (Box 9)
    - Correspondence and information about books for the festival, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Workshop questionnaire, undated (Box 9)
    - Children Are Many Colors drafts, correspondence, grants, etc., 1977-1980 (Box 9)
    - Research on films for the festival, 1978-1980 (Box 9)
    - Grant reports and evaluations, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation report and correspondence for the festival, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Evaluator's report on the Third World Children Book and Film Festival, 1981 Jan. (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous notes and documents re: children's literature, undated (Box 9)
- Film Work, 1966-2011; 5
  This series contains two subseries: Blackside, Inc., and Northern Light Productions. Files are arranged loosely by project or documentary. Additional research materials from these projects can be found in the Subject Files Series.
  Blackside, Inc., includes some of Richardson's research and manuscripts from the production of Eyes on the Prize and Eyes on the Prize II, as well as scripts and accompanying publications from the production of Malcolm X: Make It Plain. The subseries documents Richardson's roles in the development and promotion of these projects and their educational components. Richardson also collected publicity and student/teacher reactions to the series.
  The Northern Light Productions subseries includes Richardson's files on the Little Rock Central High School historical exhibits, Scarred Justice: The Orangeburg Massacre project; and Slave Catchers/Slave Resisters and its spin-off projects on slavery in New England.
  - Blackside, 1966-2011; 11
    - Blackside press packets, undated (Box 10)
    - Billed hours and research notes for Blackside, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize production, photograph, correspondence, photocopies, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize research, clippings on Detroit/Chicago collected by JR, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize research clippings collected by JR, 1966-1968 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize interview transcripts, 1985-2006 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize publicity/clippings, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize, Voices of Freedom manuscript w/ JR's comments/edits, undated (Box 10)
      Chapter 20: "I Am the Greatest"
    - Eyes on the Prize, Voices of Freedom manuscript w/ JR's comments/edits, undated (Box 10)
      Chapter 16: "Malcolm X"
    - Eyes on the Prize, Voices of Freedom manuscript w/ JR's comments/edits, undated (Box 10)
      Chapter 17: "On Daley's Plantation"
    - Eyes on the Prize, Voices of Freedom manuscript w/ JR's comments/edits, undated (Box 10)
      Chapter 29: "The Gary Conference"
    - Eyes on the Prize video release, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 10)
      re: Eyes presentation, from students/teachers
    - Student reactions re: JR guest lecture on Eyes on the Prize, 1995 (Box 10)
    - "Teaching Eyes on the Prize: Teaching Democracy" by JR, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize promos, correspondence, edits, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize clippings and articles, 1995-2011 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize re-airing Teacher Advisory Group correspondence, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize re-airing on PBS: publicity, 2005-2008 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize study guide by Facing History, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize II soundtrack notes, undated (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize II index draft, 1993 (Box 10)
    - Eyes on the Prize I and II: publicity booklet and clippings, undated (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain script, 1993 (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain script, with notes, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain Routledge volume notes, research, 1966-1990s and undated (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain Routledge volumem JR essay drafts, 1994-1996 (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain Routledge volume correspondence, agreements, etc, 1994-1996 (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain Routlege volume, essay by JR on Teaching Malcom X, undated (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain student reactions, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain American Experience re-airing, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain press/reviews, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Malcolm X: Make it Plain, production team update folder, 1995 (Box 10)
      re: re-airing
    - Africa documentary correspondence, proposals, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - Northern Light Productions, 1967-2010; 12
    - Long Road to Justice transcripts, 2000; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - A Fragile Freedom review and synopsis, 2003 (Box 11)
    - Lewis and Clark exhibit film captioning, 2003 (Box 11)
    - Slave Catchers, Slave Resisters contract, correspondence, promos, etc., 2004-2007 (Box 11)
    - Slave Catchers, Slave Resisters proposal, 2005 (Box 11)
    - Slave Catchers, Slave Resisters correspondence with Steven Hahn, 2006 (Box 11)
    - Slavery and the Making of New York press and publicity, 2005 (Box 11)
    - Slavery in New England proposal, correspondence, and research, 2006 (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project correspondence with the NPS, 2007 (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project proposals, 2006-2007 (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project research/news clippings (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project contract, notes, etc., 2006-2007 (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project filming/logistics, 2007 (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project scripts, 2007 (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project transcripts/interview notes (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project budgets and schedules, 2007 (Box 11)
    - Little Rock Central High School project National Historic Site opening, 2007 (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg Massacre documentary: Cleveland Sellars research, 1967-2002 (Box 11)
      Photocopies.
    - Orangeburg Massacre research, 2007-2008 (Box 11, Cd RL10177-ECD-001)
      Includes CD of scans resulting from a FOIA request regarding the Orangeburg Massacre.
    - Orangeburg Massacre documentary: re-creation photographs, 2007 (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg Massacre memorial, 2001 (Box 11)
      Clippings.
    - Orangeburg Massacre documentary correspondence, 2006-2010 (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg Massacre documentary screenings and events, 2009-2012 (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg Massacre documentary reviews and press (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg Massacre documentary project notes, 2007-2009 (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg project roster/participants, undated (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg Massacre documentary script, revisions, correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 11)
    - Orangeburg Massacre invoices, 2006-2008 (Box 11)
    - Scarred Justice: The Orangeburg Massacre 1968 premiere at the NAACP Convention, 2009 (Box 11)
    - Rosters/contact sheets for various projects (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence/research for various projects (Box 11)
- Project Files, 1972-2012; 6
  Richardson's "work products," as she referred to them, have been arranged alphabetically in this Project Files Series. Dates range from the 1970s through the 2000s, and include materials documenting Richardson's service on various committees, panels, and campaigns, as well as some of her articles and writings (listed by publication title). A significant amount of files are grouped under the SNCC Alumni heading, referring to reunions, conferences, and other post-civil rights movement projects undertaken by Richardson relating to SNCC.
  - Birmingham Civil Rights Institute, 2000 (Box 12)
    Curriculum review and notes
  - Black Community Crusade for Children, 1995 (Box 12)
    Ella Baker Child Policy Training Institute
  - Black Film Institute, University of D.C., 1977-1978 (Box 12)
    Consulting work
  - Black Student Fund, 1973-1976 (Box 12)
    Annual reports and correspondence from Richardson's tenure as director.
  - Black Women in the U.S. encyclopedia, 1991 (Box 12)
    Materials from Richardson's entry on Jean Wheeler Smith
  - Boston Review article/interview, "A Rebirth of Freedom Summer?", 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Center for Documentary Arts, 2011 (Box 12)
    "This Light of Ours: Activist Photographers of the Civil Rights Movement" National Advisory Committee
  - Choices Program, 2012 (Box 12)
    Freedom Now: Civil Rights Movement in Mississippi interview, etc.
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1993 (Box 12)
    Multicultural Board
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1997 (Box 12)
    Office of Education and Programming
  - Council on Foundations, 1998 (Box 12)
    Film and Video Festival Committee
  - Essence "Speak" column, "We Need a Movement", 1985-1987 (Box 12)
    Richardson's drafts, correspondence
  - Family Name documentary, 1996 (Box 12)
    Consultant
  - Fellowship article, "Mississippi Burning", 1989 Jun. (Box 12)
    Includes Richardson's clippings, notes, drafts, correspondence.
  - Footsteps Magazine article, "Reflections and Memories: An Interview with Ezell A. Blair" by J.R., 2000 (Box 12)
  - Greensboro International Civil Rights Museum, 2009; 3 folders (Box 12)
    Panels research for In Memorium and Women in the Movement exhibits
  - Independent Television Service (ITS), 1994 (Box 12)
    Everyday Life in America panel
  - Jackson State University, 1995 Oct. 4-6 (Box 12)
    Fannie Lou Hamer lecture series
  - JFK Library Poetry and Politics, 1998-1999 (Box 12)
  - Massachusetts Review article, "Womanpower and SNCC", 2011 (Box 12)
  - Marion Barry's mayorial campaign, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Mi Puerto Rico documentary, 1994-1996 (Box 12)
    Advisory correspondence, proposals, etc.
  - National Association of Independent Schools, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
    Minority Affairs Committee materials
  - National Black Parents Organization, 1974 (Box 12)
    Newsletter and correspondence
  - National Black Political Convention, 1972 (Box 12)
    Fact sheets, agendas, committee lists, etc.
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
    Humanities Projects in Media panel
  - National Museum of Natural History, 1994-1996 (Box 13)
    African Voices Project
  - National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, 2010 (Box 13)
    Richardson was the audiotour narrator. Includes script, etc.
  - Patriots Trail Girl Scout Program, 1993-1996 (Box 13)
    Leadership award and recipe book
  - POV: Television with a Point of View, 1995-1996 (Box 13)
    Editorial committee
  - Rainbow TV Works, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Ron Settles police brutality case, 1981 (Box 13)
    Includes clippings, notes, fact sheets, and 2014 note from J.R. on her work in the case.
  - The Second Wave documentary, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
    Advisory Committee
  - SNCC Alumni: Reunion minutes, 1976 Nov. 6 (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: Curtis Hayes Muhammad jailing in Liberia, 1988 (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: meetings/conferences, 1978-1988 (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: Ella J. Baker Birthday Committee, 1978 (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: Amzie Moore fundraising, undated (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: Joyce Ladner speech transcript, 2000 Apr. 14 (Box 13)
    From SNCC Reunion
  - SNCC Alumni: Gloria Richardson Dandridge interview transcript, 1998 Feb. 7 (Disk RL10177-FL3-001, Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: Freedom Summer reunion, 1994 (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: Raleigh conference, 2000 (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: Freedom Summer reunion, conference at Miami University in Ohio, 2008-2010 (Box 13)
  - SNCC Alumni: reunion and conference, Brown University, 2010 (Box 13)
  - Teens as Community Resources, 1992-1993 (Box 13)
    Board of Directors
  - United South End Settlements, 1998 (Box 13)
  - U.S. Dept. of Education, 1980 Aug. 8 (Box 13)
    Request for proposal for production of ESAA Radio Series
  - WNET Humanities Initiative, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 13)
    Advisor; includes reports, correspondence, clippings, etc.
- Event Files, 1974-2014; 7
  The Event Files Series has been loosely arranged chronologically, with correspondence, pamphlets, and ephemera from many of Richardson's engagements sorted by year. Events with substantial documentation have been filed individually following the "general" files for that year.
  - General events, 1974-1977; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - General events, 1986 (Box 13)
  - General events, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - The Films of the Civil Rights, 1989 Jun. 16-24 (Box 23)
    Uncorrected draft program.
  - PBS Rocky Mountain Retreat, 1990 May 4-6 (Box 13)
  - General events, 1991-1995; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Social Venture Network Conference, 1995 Nov. 5-8 (Box 13)
  - General events, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Ford Foundation: Future of Public Service Media symposium, 1996 (Box 14)
  - General events, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Leadership America program, 1997 Jun. 21-25 (Box 14)
  - General events, 1998 (Box 14)
  - JFK Library: Media and the Civil Rights Revolution, 1998 Mar. 24 (Box 14)
  - Southern Africa Film Festival, 1998 Sept. 25-Oct. 5 (Box 14)
  - International Documentary Congress 3, 1998 Oct. 28-30 (Box 14)
  - Annie E. Casey Foundation, 1998 Dec. 10 (Box 14)
  - Henry Hampton memorial service, 1998 Dec. 12 (Box 14)
  - General events, 1999 (Box 14)
  - WKKF Devolution Networking meeting, 1999 Oct. 5-7 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2000 (Box 14)
  - Women in Film and Video NE Image Awards, 2000 May 16 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Writers on Writing, 2001 May 7 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2002-2003; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Boston Women's Fund Annual Benefit, 2003 May 17 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2004-2005; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - James Forman memorial, 2005 Apr. 30 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2006-2007; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - NAACP Civil Rights School, 2007 Nov. 8-11 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2008-2009; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - National Council on Public History annual meeting, 2009 Apr. 2-5 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2010 (Box 14)
  - Oral History Association conference, 2010 Oct. 27-31 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2011-2012; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Worchester Museum: Images of the 1960s lecture, 2012 Oct. 13 (Box 14)
  - YWCA Cambridge Tribute, 2012 Oct. 18 (Box 14)
  - General events, 2013-2014 and undated; 3 folders (Box 23, Box 14)
- Personal Materials, 1960-2014; 8
  Richardon's Personal Materials Series includes her files from various interviews and press coverage she has received; personal correspondence files arranged loosely by year; miscellaneous photographs and clippings; and her FOIA files from 1983. The FOIA subseries includes redacted FBI files from the agency's surveillance of Richardson during 1964 and 1969, both for her work in SNCC and her affiliations with the Black Panther Party during her years at Drum and Spear.
  - Interviews, 1986-2014; 13
    - Ahmad, Muhammad, undated (Box 15)
      SNCC chapter with interview material from JR and accompanying letter
    - Bates, Karen Grigsely, 2013 August 20 (Box 15)
      Interview notes
    - Brewley-Corbin, D. Natasha, 2006 (Box 15)
      SNCC paper, correspondence
    - Campbell, Mary Schmidt, 1994 (Box 15)
      Transcript of sessions from Conference on Black Cinema, correspondence
    - Cohen, Benji, undated (Box 15)
      Paper with interview material and correspondence
    - Duartbell, Janet, undated (Box 15)
      Interview transcript and personal note
    - The History Makers, 2007-2014; 2 folders (Dvd RL10177-DVD-054, Dvd RL10177-DVD-053, Box 15)
      Interview material and correspondence; website bio
    - Koch, Aimee, 2001 (Box 15)
      Student thesis
    - Koppe, Liz, 1999 (Box 15)
      Copy of paper, correspondence between Koppe and Richardson
    - Monasebian, Dayla, 1992 (Box 15)
      Copy of paper, correspondence
    - Lyle, Desiree, 2001 (Box 15)
      Paper with interview material, personal note
    - Lyons, Courtney, undated (Box 15)
      Interview materials on Prathia Hall for dissertation
    - Oltman, Adele, 1986-1987 (Box 15)
      Interview transcripts, correspondence
    - Preston, Tiffany, 2007 (Box 15)
      Interview log, correspondence
    - Ransby, Barbara, 2002, 2005 (Box 15)
      Ella Baker interview material and correspondence, follow-up
    - Robnett, Belinda, 1996 (Box 15)
      interview excerpts with edits by Richardson, correspondence
    - Sattin, Carolyn, 2002 (Box 15)
      Women in SNCC, A New Perspective
    - Stanford, Maxwell, 2002 (Box 15)
      SNCC chapter with interview material, correspondence
    - Theoharis, Jeanne, 1991 June 24 (Box 15)
      Thesis and accompanying letter
    - Tilghman, Laura, 2005 Apr. 21 (Box 15)
      Mississippi Freedom Summer radio interview.
    - Valk, Anne, 1995-1996 (Box 15)
      Interview transcript, correspondence
    - Varela, Maria, 2008 (Box 15)
      Interview questions, correspondence
    - Veterans of the Civil Rights Movement: Judy Richardson interview, 2007 February (Box 15)
      Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1960-2014; 14
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: interviews and interview notes, 1995-2014 and undated (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence separated from the AV Series, 2000s (Box 15)
    - Correspondence re: SNCC topics, 2000s (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, general, 1960s-1970s (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, general, 1980s (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, general, 1990-1992 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, general, 1993-1999 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, general, 2000-2004 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, general, 2005-2006 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, general, 2007-2014 (Box 15)
    - Recommendation letters, undated (Box 15)
  - Photographs and clippings, 1980s-2000s; 15
    - Wall photos from above Richardson's desk, undated (Box 15)
    - Personal photographs, undated (Box 15)
    - SNCC/Civil Rights photograph print-outs, undated (Box 15)
    - Clippings about Richardson or including her photograph, 1980s-2000s (Box 15)
  - FOIA, 1964-1983; 16
    - FOIA-FBI files re: SNCC, 1964, 1983 (Box 15)
    - FOIA-FBI files re: SNCC and Drum and Spear Bookstore, 1969, 1983 (Box 15)
- Subject Files, 9
  The Subject Files Series includes Richardson's research materials and other miscellany she collected on a variety of topics, including civil rights figures, children's literature, and slavery.
  - African American history (Box 16)
  - Baker, Ella (Box 16)
  - Black children's literature, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Black Panthers/Black Power (Box 16)
  - Bond, Julian (Box 16)
  - Children's book reviews (Box 16)
  - Civil rights movement (Box 16)
  - Cox, Frankie Clark (Box 16)
    Short story: Better to Die First
  - Education (Box 16)
  - Interracial books for children (Box 16)
  - King, Martin Luther (Box 16)
  - Obama, Barack (Box 16)
  - Queen Nzinga (Box 16)